let's represent the sum of the first n
cubes using cubic stacks of Cubes like
this here we pictured 1 cubed plus two
cubed plus three cubed and so on in this
particular instance we stopped at n
equals 4 but we can imagine a similar
stack for any n now we decompose each
cubic stack into an L-shaped flat nomon
the levels of the odd cubes break up
perfectly to fit around the previous
gnomon but the even cubes don't work
quite as well instead we have to take
one level and split it into two separate
pieces as shown here when n is four once
we've broken up each Cube into a flat
nomon we see that all the small cubes
have been arranged in a perfect square
where the side length is given by the
sum of the first and positive integers
this means that the sum of the first n
positive cubes is equal to the square of
the sum of the first n positive integers